<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on behind the keyboard</title><link>https://blog.alileza.me/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on behind the keyboard</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:24:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.alileza.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Communication Is Key</title><link>https://blog.alileza.me/posts/communication-is-key/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:24:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.alileza.me/posts/communication-is-key/</guid><description>Humans have a lot of things on their minds, and we are still getting surprises from what the mind can do. That is pretty much what made life interesting.
You could see something coloured yellow, and others disagree. And from that, you know that we perceive the same thing in a different ways.
That is why we have to understand when we communicate we get to prepare ourselves to know how to communicate, with an audience.</description></item><item><title>Good observability is simply more important than good testing</title><link>https://blog.alileza.me/posts/good-observability-is-simply-better-than-good-testing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 23:23:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.alileza.me/posts/good-observability-is-simply-better-than-good-testing/</guid><description>In most cases, good observability is simply more important than good testing. As we all know
There is no system that immune to failure, so we need to be ready to recover
Being able to recover from failure quickly, is pretty much how important observability is. In this case, I would slightly mention 3 phases of incident
Alert fired, it can come from system or user, if it comes from the user, that’s a pretty good sign that we don’t have a good alert rules Observe the issue, it is the phase where we try to figure out what is wrong with the system Fix the issue, it is a phase where we execute a task to bring us to a healthy state From the picture above, we can see that having good observability will help reduce the Mean Time to Recover, and it gives us the leverage to be able to make changes more rapidly because our ability to recover from problems is good enough.</description></item><item><title>What is programming? and why should I care?</title><link>https://blog.alileza.me/posts/what-is-programming-and-why-should-i-care/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 23:04:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.alileza.me/posts/what-is-programming-and-why-should-i-care/</guid><description>Background I often hear from friends the same impression about computer programming, that it is hard and complicated. I do understand that point of view, I do feel that way, for a lot of different things. But I feel like that is caused by we learned about computer programming in a wrong perspective, such as we watched in movies or tv shows, that shows all code changing in a fast pace, that we never saw before in our life, to describe programming.</description></item></channel></rss>